Roy Crane Papers
Roy Crane Papers
1908-1977
Crane, Roy
72 linear ft.
Approximately 6,000 Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy comic strips and approximately 11,700 Buz Sawyer comic strips in various media (original cartoons, proofs and tear sheets), examples of other Crane comic strips, biographical material, correspondence, original drawings and sketches, promotional materials, research materials, writings and artifacts.
148912
Biographical History
Royston C. Crane (1901-1977), known as Roy Crane, was an American cartoonist. He was the creator of the long-running newspaper comic strips Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy and Buz Sawyer.
Crane, son of Judge and Mrs. R. C. Crane, was born in 1901 in Abilene, Texas, and grew up in Sweetwater, Texas. He attended Hardin-Simmons University in 1918 and the University of Texas from 1919 to 1922, later studying briefly at the Chicago Academy of Fine Arts. In 1924, he started the comic strip, Wash Tubbs, for the Newspaper Enterprise Association in Cleveland. Later he introduced another character, "Captain Easy", into the strip, for whom the Sunday version was ultimately named. In 1943, Roy Crane left NEA to launch his new creation, Buz Sawyer, for King Features Syndicate in New York. Both Crane creations eventually ran well into the late 1980s.
Crane was honored with the prestigious Reuben Award by the National Cartoonists Society in 1950. He was also awarded the Gold Medal Award for Distinguished Public Service, the highest honor the navy can bestow on civilians, from the United States Navy for his fictional adventures of Buz Sawyer. In 1961, he received the Silver Lady Award from the Banshee club—a group of artists, editors, and writers in New York. Mr. Crane was honored with a Doctorate of Human Letters from Rollins College. He established the Roy Crane Award in Arts at the University of Texas to encourage independent achievement in creative writing, art, music, and drama in January 1965. Roy Crane died in 1977.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Roy Crane Papers contains comic strips, art and artifacts, biographical material and personal papers, corespondence, drawings and sketches, promotional material, published material, research material, and writings. The evolution of the various permutations of Crane's original feature is a bit tangled, but in rough terms the daily version was titled "Wash Tubbs", while the Sunday feature ran with the title "Captain Easy". Eventually, around 1949, the two strips both began to carry the title "Captain Easy", but many local papers continued to use the old titles for many years.
The vast bulk of the collection consists of Comic strips in various formats from Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy (1924-1945) and Buz Sawyer (1943-1977). Comic strip formats include original cartoons, tear sheets and proofs. Typically, until about the late 1950s, Crane kept proofs/tear sheets in large scrapbooks, with Sunday and daily versions ordered separately in chronological order. After 1957, proofs were kept as loose sheets (6 strips per sheet for dailies). Crane's original cartoons are also ordered separately in chronological order. For the first few years of the Captain Easy Sunday strip, Crane produced large, hand-colored panels. Most of these are in 2 pieces, but about a dozen or so are still intact as single pieces. Often, especially in the early years of Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy, Crane cut his drawings into multiple pieces—probably to expedite mailing, but also for his own purposes (image files, examples for assistants, etc.). Whenever possible, identifiable fragments and partial cartoons have been integrated with other cartoon holdings (in chronological order); a number of these fragments, however, have not been integrated, and can be found together under the grouping "Cartoon Fragments".
In addition to holdings of Crane's primary comic strips, the collection also contains examples of other, short-lived and pilot strips that Crane produced. There are large format color proofs from Frank Battle and The Rise of Radio Rudolph, as well as original cartoon drawings from a never-realized travel feature. The collection also contains several tear sheet examples of the supplemental Wash Tubbs games feature, and a few tear sheets representing the early, short-lived Sunday version of Wash Tubbs.
Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy material includes daily cartoons and Sunday cartoons. Art media for the daily cartoons include traces of graphite, blue pencil, pasteovers, pen and ink on Craftint board or illustration board; dimensions vary approx. 5 x 17 ½ in. to 7 ½ x 25 ½ in. Art media for the Sunday cartoons until 1935 include traces of graphite, blue pencil, paste-overs, watercolor, brush, pen and ink on illustration board; overall dimensions approx. 22 ¾ x 24 in., most in 2 pieces). After 1935, traces of graphite, blue pencil, paste-overs, brush, pen and ink on illustration board, overall dimensions approx. 21 ½ x 28 in. (most in 2 pieces). For the daily proofs, most are approx. 3 x 8 ½ in. on newsprint (strips pasted into scrapbooks). For the Sunday proofs, most are 9 ½ x 13 in. in color on newsprint (pasted into scrapbooks).
Buz Sawyer material includes daily cartoons and Sunday cartoons. Art media for the daily cartoons include traces of graphite, blue pencil, scratchings, opaque white, brush, pen and ink on Craftint board (some on illustration board), approx. 6 x 18 in. Art media for the Sunday cartoons include traces of graphite, blue pencil, opaque white, pasteovers, brush, pen and ink on illustration board, dimensions vary, most approx. 18 x 26 in. Daily proof sheet (1943-1965): dimensions vary, most 11 ½ x 19 ½ in. on newsprint (6 strips per sheet). Fir tge daily proof sheet (1965-1977): most approx. 8 ½ x 17 in. on glossy paper (6 strips per sheet). Sunday proof: dimensions vary, most approx. 10 ½ x 14 ½ in color on glossy paper (all in black and white starting 1965).
In addition to original artwork for the above comic strips, the collection also contains a significant amount of material related to the production and distribution of the comic strips. Art and artifacts contains some of Crane's artistic materials, including sample drawings and scrapbooks/manuals on "How to Draw Buz Sawyer" and "How to Write Buz Sawyer," as well as cartoons by other artists.
Biographical material and personal papers includes awards, biographical and autobiographical sketches, photographs, a few financial items, and miscellaneous personal material.
Correspondence represents professional communications, including correspondence with syndicate representatives (both NEA and King Features), assistant artists (including Leslie Turner, Bela Zaboly, Joe King, Al Wenzel and Clark Haas), and a substantial amount of correspondence between Crane and various U.S. government entities, especially the U.S. Navy. There is a separate subseries of correspondence between Crane and his assistant Clark Haas which documents their working relationship.
There are preliminary Drawings and sketches from every phase of Crane's career, from juvenilia to his published strips.
Promotional material consists of syndicate-produced announcements, sample strips, etc. for Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy, Buz Sawyer and other Roy Crane strips.
Published material includes clippings about Crane and his work as well as assorted published examples of his work such as sheet music and magazine covers.
Research material for Buz Sawyer and Wash Tubbs includes notes, notebooks, pamphlets, clippings, photographs and so on.
Writings, mostly by Crane, includes notes, drafts and typescripts reflecting the development of story scenarios and continuities (including accumulated research material and notebooks), as well as Crane's thoughts about his work and the history and art form of the comic strip.
Arrangement of the Collection
Original comic strip art is arranged first. The other series follow in alphabetical order by series title. Within each series, material is arranged alphabetically by type or title.
Related Material
For additional original cartoons from the Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy comic strip, see the
Leslie Turner Cartoons
. In addition, has an 18-volume reprint edition of the full run of Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy. Please see to locate this set.
Subject and Genre Headings
Art -- Cartoonists; Bairnsfather, Bruce, 1887-; Crane, Roy.; Haas, Clark.; King, Joe.; Mendelsohn, Jack.; Schlensker, Hank.; Turner, Leslie, 1899-1988.; Wenzel, Al.; Zaboly, Bela.; King Features Syndicate.; National Cartoonists Society.; Newspaper Enterprise Association.; United States. -- Navy.; University of Texas at Austin.; Buz Sawyer (comic strip); Captain Easy (comic strip); Wash Tubbs (comic strip); Adventure stories -- Comic books, strips, etc.; American wit and humor, Pictorial.; Caricatures and cartoons -- United States.; Cartoonists -- United States.; Cold War -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Comic books, strips, etc. -- United States.; War -- Comic books, strips, etc.; Articles.; Cartoons (humorous images); Clippings (information artifacts); Comic strips.; Correspondence.; Drawings (visual works); Manuscripts (document genre); Notebooks.; Photographs.; Posters.; Proofs (printed matter); Scrapbooks.; Sketches.; Tear sheets.; Cartoonists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Roy Crane.
Inventory
- Comic strips, original art
  - Wash Tubbs/Captain Easy comic strips, approximately 6,000 comic strips
    Click here for detailed inventory.
    - Daily cartoons
      - Daily cartoons, 1926 Dec 30-1934 Jun 19 (Oversize 1)
      - Daily cartoons, 1934 Aug 17-1939 Mar 2 (Oversize 2)
      - Daily cartoons, 1940 Feb 24 -1940 Dec 28 (Oversize 3)
      - Daily cartoons, 1941 Jan 10 -1941 Dec 30 (Oversize 4)
      - Daily cartoons, 1942 Jan 1 -1945 Apr 14 (Oversize 5)
    - Sunday cartoons
      - Sunday cartoons, 1933 Aug 20-1934 Dec 30 (Oversize 6)
        For the following Sunday cartoons, see Oversize 8 below: 9/17/33, 10/8/33, 12/3/33, 12/10/33, 12/17/33, 12/24/33, 1/7/34, 7/15/34, 8/26/34, 10/7/34, 11/18/34, 12/23/34.
      - Sunday cartoons, 1935 Jan 6-1935 Dec 15 (Oversize 7)
        For the following Sunday cartoons, see Oversize 8 below: 1/13/35, 9/29/35.
      - Sunday cartoons, oversize color, 1933 Sep 17-1935 Sep 29 (Oversize 8)
        Specific dates: 9/17/33, 10/8/33, 12/3/33, 12/10/33, 12/17/33, 12/24/33, 1/7/34, 7/15/34, 8/26/34, 10/7/34, 11/18/34, 12/23/34, 1/13/35, 9/29/35
      - Sunday cartoons, 1936 Jan 5 -1936 Dec 27 (Oversize 9)
      - Sunday cartoons, 1937 Apr 4 -1939 Dec 31 (Oversize 10)
      - Sunday cartoons, 1940 Jan 14 -1940 Oct 13 (Oversize 11)
    - Daily proofs/tear sheets
      - [Scrapbook 1], 1924 Apr 15-1924 Dec 23 (Volume 1)
      - [Scrapbook 2], 1924 Dec 24-1925 Jun 9 (Volume 2)
      - [Scrapbook 3], 1925 May 30-1927 Dec 31 (Volume 3)
      - [Scrapbook 4], 1928 Jan 2-1930 Jan 4 (Volume 4)
      - [Scrapbook 5], 1930 Jan 6-1932 Jan 2 (Volume 5)
      - [Scrapbook 6], 1932 Jan 4-1933 Dec 30 (Volume 6)
      - [Scrapbook 7], 1934 Jan 1-1936 Jan 4 (Volume 7)
      - [Scrapbook 8], 1936 Jan 6-1938 Jan 1 (Volume 8)
      - [Scrapbook 9], 1938 Jan 3-1939 Dec 30 (Volume 9)
      - [Scrapbook 10], 1940 Jan 1-1941 Dec 27; 1942 Mar 30-1942 May 9 (Volume 10)
      - [Scrapbook 11], 1942 Apr 21-1942 Nov 14; 1943 Mar 15-1943 May 29 (Volume 11)
    - Sunday proofs/tear sheets, Captain Easy
      - [Scrapbook 12], 1933 Jul 30-1934 Dec 30 (Volume 12)
      - [Scrapbook 13], 1935 Jan 6-1935 Dec 29 (Volume 13)
      - [Scrapbook 14], 1936 Jan 12-1936 Dec 27 (Volume 14)
      - [Scrapbook 15], 1937 Jan 3-1937 Dec 26 (Volume 15)
      - [Scrapbook 16], 1938 Jan 2-1938 Dec 25 (Volume 16)
      - [Scrapbook 17], 1939 Jan 1-1939 Dec 31 (Volume 17)
      - [Scrapbook 18], 1940 Jan 7-1941 Dec 28 (Volume 18)
      - [Scrapbook 19], 1942 Jan 4-1943 Jul 4 (Volume 19)
    - Sunday tear sheets, Wash Tubbs, 1927 Mar 27-1927 Apr 24; in color, 5 ¼ x 14 ¾ in.; 5 (Oversize 12)
  - Buz Sawyer, approximately 11,700 comic strips
    - Daily cartoons
      - Daily cartoons, 1943 Nov 4-1949 Apr 26 (Oversize 19)
      - Daily cartoons, 1951 Jan 1-1954 Feb 3 (Oversize 20)
      - Daily cartoons, 1955 Jan 10-1955 Sep 30 (Oversize 21)
      - Daily cartoons, 1955 Oct 1-1956 Jun 6 (Oversize 22)
      - Daily cartoons, 1956 Oct 15-1957 Jun 27 (Oversize 23)
      - Daily cartoons, 1957 Jul 1-1957 Dec 31 (Oversize 24)
      - Daily cartoons, 1958 Jan 1-1958 Jun 30 (Oversize 25)
      - Daily cartoons, 1958 Jul 1-1958 Dec 30 (Oversize 26)
      - Daily cartoons, 1959 Jan 1-1959 Jul 31 (Oversize 27)
      - Daily cartoons, 1959 Aug 1-1959 Dec 30 (Oversize 28)
      - Daily cartoons, 1960 Jan 1-1960 Jun 30 (Oversize 29)
      - 1960 Jul 1-1960 Dec 31 (Oversize 30)
      - Daily cartoons, 1961 Jan 10-1961 Jun 30 (Oversize 31)
      - Daily cartoons, 1961 Jul 1-1961 Dec 30 (Oversize 32)
      - Daily cartoons, 1962 Jan 1-1962 Jun 30 (Oversize 33)
      - Daily cartoons, 1962 Jul 2-1962 Dec 31 (Oversize 34)
      - Daily cartoons, 1963 Jan 1-1963 May 30 (Oversize 35)
      - Daily cartoons, 1963 Jun 1-1963 Dec 31 (Oversize 36)
      - Daily cartoons, 1964 Jan 1-1964 Jun 30 (Oversize 37)
      - Daily cartoons, 1964 Jul 1-1964 Dec 31 (Oversize 38)
      - Daily cartoons, 1965 Jan 1-1965 Jun 30 (Oversize 39)
      - Daily cartoons, 1965 Jul 1-1965 Dec 30 (Oversize 40)
      - Daily cartoons, 1966 Jan 1-1966 Jun 28 (Oversize 41)
      - Daily cartoons, 1966 Jul 2-1966 Dec 30 (Oversize 42)
    - Sunday cartoons
      - Sunday cartoons, 1943 Dec 26-1949 Nov 27 (Oversize 43)
      - Sunday cartoons, 1950 Jan 29-1955 Dec 25 (Oversize 44)
      - Sunday cartoons, 1956 Jan 1-1956 Dec 30; 1960 Jan 3-1960 Dec 25 (Oversize 45)
      - Sunday cartoons, 1961 Jan 8-1962 Jul 29 (Oversize 46)
      - Sunday cartoons, 1962 Aug 5-1963 Dec 29 (Oversize 47)
      - Sunday cartoons, 1964 Jan 5-1965 Jul 25 (Oversize 48)
      - Sunday cartoons, 1965 Aug 1-1966 Dec 25 (Oversize 49)
    - Daily proofs
      - [Scrapbook 21], 1943 Nov 1-1945 Mar 17 (Volume 21)
      - [Scrapbook 22], 1945 Mar 19-1946 Oct 19 (Volume 22)
      - [Scrapbook 28], 1946 Oct 14-1947 Jun 28 (Volume 28)
      - [Scrapbook 23], 1947 Jun 30-1948 Nov 27 (Volume 23)
      - [Scrapbook 24], 1948 Nov 22-1952 Jun 14; samples of Buz Sawyer strips from Peru, Sweden, Uruguay, Finland and comic book cover from Rio pasted on inside of front and back cover of scrapbook (Volume 24)
      - [Scrapbook 25], 1952 Jun 16-1956 Mar 3 (Volume 25)
      - Daily proofs, 1954 Mar 1-1955 Jul 9; 1961 Jul 24-1963 Mar 30 (Oversize 50)
      - Daily proofs, 1963 Apr 8-1965 Jun 30 (Oversize 51)
      - Daily proofs, 1965 Jul 1-1970 Dec 31 (Oversize 52)
      - Daily proofs, 1971 Jan 1-1977 Sep 3 (Oversize 53)
    - Sunday proofs
      - [Scrapbook 26], 1943 Nov 28-1944 Dec 24 (Volume 26)
      - [Scrapbook 27], 1944 Dec 31-1946 Oct 13 (Volume 27)
      - [Scrapbook 28], 1946 Oct 20-1947 Mar 2 (Volume 28)
      - [Scrapbook 29], 1947 Mar 9-1948 Dec 26 (Volume 29)
      - [Scrapbook 30], 1949 Jan 2-1952 Jul 20 (Volume 30)
      - [Scrapbook 31], 1952 Jul 20-1956 Apr 22 (Volume 31)
      - [Scrapbook 32], 1956 Apr 29-1957 Sep 8 (Volume 32)
      - Sunday proofs, 1957 Sep 15-1960 Dec 25 (Oversize 54)
      - Sunday proofs, 1961 Jan 1-1964 Dec 27 (Oversize 55)
      - Sunday proofs, 1965 Jan 3-1974 May 19 (Oversize 56)
  - Other comic strips
    - Frank Battle, Sunday proof, 1930; in color, 15 ¾ x 22 in.; handwritten note from Crane: "meant for publication by NEA in early 1930, only two pages were drawn before the feature was dropped due to the Depression"; 1 (Oversize 12)
      See also Drawings and sketches: Frank Battle sketches.
    - The Rise of Radio Rudolph, Sunday proof, circa 1930; in color, 12 ½ x 19 in. (Oversize 12)
    - Travel feature, pencil cartoons, 1928; pencil, pen and ink on illustration board, 14 ¾ x 15 ½ in.; handwritten note from Crane: "Once, about 1928, I dreamed of doing a travel feature that would take me endlessly around the world. I was advised to stick with "Wash Tubbs". This was the sample I submitted to about 2 syndicates"; 8 items (Oversize 12)
    - Wash Tubbs games
      - "The Tubbsy Treasure Hunt", September 11, 1932; Sunday color tear sheet, approx. 5 ½ x 15 in. (Oversize 12)
      - "Bull's Eye!", September 18, 1932; Sunday color tear sheet, approx. 5 ½ x 15 in. (Oversize 12)
      - "World Series!", September 25, 1932; Sunday color tear sheet, approx. 5 ½ x 15 in. (Oversize 12)
      - "Bear Hunt!", October 2, 1932; Sunday color tear sheet, approx. 5 ½ x 15 in. (Oversize 12)
      - "Touch-Down!", October 9, 1932; Sunday color tear sheet, approx. 5 ½ x 15 in. (Oversize 12)
      - "Lost in the Wilds of Africa", October 16, 1932; Sunday color tear sheet, approx. 5 ½ x 15 in. (Oversize 12)
      - "Steeple Chase!", October 23, 1932; Sunday color tear sheet, approx. 5 ½ x 15 in. (Oversize 12)
      - "Big Game Hunt!", October 30, 1932; Sunday color tear sheet, approx. 5 ½ x 15 in. (Oversize 12)
      - "Hare and Hounds", November 6, 1932; Sunday color tear sheet, approx. 5 ½ x 15 in. (Oversize 12)
      - "Cross Country", November 27, 1932; Sunday color tear sheet, approx. 5 ½ x 15 in. (Oversize 12)
      - "Pot Shot", December 3, 1932; Sunday color tear sheet, approx. 5 ½ x 15 in. (Oversize 12)
    - Untitled strip [chorus girls], undated; original cartoon with traces of graphite, blue pencil, pen and ink on illustration board, 7 x 18 in.); cartoon depicts a series of chorus girls with labels: "attractive margin", "shelf room", "doubtful quality", etc. (Oversize 12)
- Art and artifacts
  - Artist tools/technical aids
    - Buz Sawyer template, Crane's template for drawing Buz Sawyer, approx. 19 x 26 ½ in.; handwritten note on board: "Key to making pages accurately-Buz Sawyer." (Oversize 12)
    - How to Draw Buz Sawyer (Scrapbook 33 and duplicate photostats), 1940s; pasted-in examples from proofs and tear sheets with handwritten captions by Crane, approx. 11 x 18 in.; handwritten note from Crane, "This book was compiled when Hank Schlensker took over the daily 'Buz Sawyer'. It was meant to show him the 'secrets' and 'tricks' of getting good effects in Benday which had taken me years to learn." (Volume 33)
    - How to Write Buz Sawyer, circa 1963; scrapbook, 150pp., typed; handwritten notes and sketches in three-ring binder (Oversize 18)
    - Shading key, Crane's key for shading patterns; pen and ink on illustration board, approx. 8 x 11 ½ in.; handwritten note: "Patterns for clothing, etc. Each kind of shading has a key number as well-B. Zaboly." (Oversize 12)
  - Cartoons by others
    - Bruce Bairnsfather cartoon [Scrapbook 20], 1947; "Old Bill" drawing, pencil on paper (11 ½ x 17 ¾ in.), inscribed to Crane by the artist (Volume 20)
    - Buz Sawyer sketches, undated; pencil sketches on illustration board, approx. 7 x 21 ¾ in.; handwritten note from Crane: "trying out a new assistant"; 5 items (Oversize 12)
    - Kid Stuff!, undated; original cartoon panel by Gene Williams, sent to Crane as a sample of the artist's work (Oversize 12)
    - Messes From Life, undated; original comic strip by Ken Muse, sent to Crane as a solicitation (Oversize 12)
    - Treasure Chest [comic book cover], 1964 Dec 31; original comic strip by unknown artist, sent to Crane as a sample of the artist's work (Oversize 12)
    - Untitled, undated; printed comic strip by Robert Connolly, sent to Crane as a sample of the artist's work (Oversize 12)
- Biographical material and personal papers
  - Autobiographical sketch, undated (before 1971); typescript by Crane on his career and the history of the comic strip, 17 pp. (Box 1)
  - Biographical Series No. 65, King Features Syndicate, undated; draft and typed copies of syndicate-issued biographical sketch of Crane done by Mel Heimer; 4 items (Box 1)
  - Financial records, 1934; 1962; 20 items (Box 1)
    Contains expense receipts for art supplies (1962), deposit slips (1934), Captain Easy expense reports (1934) and certificate of payment for house construction (1940)
  - Home landscaping plans for Crane house, undated (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous personal papers, 1943; 1953,; 1962,; undated; 4 items (Box 1)
    Contains typed list of newspapers using Buz Sawyer (1943), notes on enhancing the reader appeal of Buz Sawyer (1953), Indiantown landowners notice (1962), voter registration card, and a handwritten "to-do-list" (undated)
  - National Cartoonists Society material, 1949-1962; 4 items (Box 1)
    Contains itinerary for "Flying Cartoonist" promotional trip (1949), NCS newsletters (1953, 1962), and program for NCS Annual Dinner (1954)
  - Photographs of Crane family, 1948; 1952; snapshots of children and calliope; 3 items (Box 1)
  - Photographs of Roy Crane, circa 1962; photographs of Crane touring various military sites, making public appearances and receiving honorary degree from Rollins College; 19 items (Box 1)
  - Roy Crane Award in the Arts at the University of Texas, 1965; letter, press releases issued by the University of Texas and clipping announcing the first winners of the award; 4 items (Box 1)
  - "Silver Lady" award (Banshees award), 1961; album of testimonials (xerox copies), original program from award ceremony, copies of newspaper articles about the ceremony and a typed copy of Crane's acceptance speech; 7 items (Oversize 14)
- Correspondence
  - Incoming correspondence
    - A, miscellaneous, 1945-1965; undated (Box 2)
    - Air Force, U.S., 1954-1964; undated (Box 2)
    - Army, U.S., 1944; undated (Box 2)
    - Aviation/Space Writers Association, 1964-1965 (Box 2)
    - B, miscellaneous, 1933-1967; undated (Box 2)
    - Badger, 1962; undated (Box 2)
    - Boughner, 1964 (Box 2)
    - C, miscellaneous, 1931-1966; undated (Box 2)
    - Crane family, 1918-1953; undated (Box 2)
    - Curtiss, 1944 (Box 2)
    - D, miscellaneous, 1934-1964; undated (Box 2)
    - Department of Health, Education and Welfare, 1962-1963 (Box 2)
    - E, miscellaneous, 1954-1966 (Box 2)
    - F, miscellaneous, 1949-1967 (Box 2)
    - Fishback & Sons, 1940 (Box 2)
    - G, miscellaneous, 1925-1964; undated (Box 2)
    - H, miscellaneous, 1931-1965; undated (Box 2)
    - J, miscellaneous, 1940-1966 (Box 2)
    - K, miscellaneous, 1949-1966; undated (Box 2)
    - King Features Syndicate, 1941-1966; undated; 5 folders (Box 4)
    - King. Joe, undated (Box 2)
    - L, miscellaneous, 1930-1967; undated (Box 2)
    - M, miscellaneous, 1947-1965; undated (Box 2)
    - N, miscellaneous, 1950-1965 (Box 3)
    - National Cartoonists Society, 1950-1966; undated (Box 3)
    - Navy, U.S., 1943-1967; undated; 3 folders (Box 3)
    - NEA Service, 1941-1948; undated (Box 3)
    - O, miscellaneous, 1948-1963 (Box 3)
    - P, miscellaneous, 19321966; undated (Box 3)
    - Phi Kappa Psi, 1951-1964 (Box 3)
    - President's Organization on Unemployment Relief, 1931 (Box 3)
    - R, miscellaneous, 1944-1965; undated (Box 3)
    - S, miscellaneous, 1948-1967; undated (Box 3)
    - State Department, U.S., 1952 (Box 3)
    - T, miscellaneous, 1951-1965; undated (Box 3)
    - Treasury Department, U.S., 1953-1962 (Box 3)
    - Turner, Leslie, 1960; undated (Box 3)
    - U, miscellaneous, 1962-1965 (Box 3)
    - University of Texas at Austin, 1953-1965 (Box 3)
    - V, miscellaneous, 1956-1967 (Box 3)
    - W, miscellaneous, 1945-1967; undated (Box 3)
    - War Department, U.S., 1943 (Box 3)
    - Wenzel, Al, 1964; undated (Box 3)
    - The Writers (club), 1934 (Box 3)
    - X, Y, Z, miscellaneous, 1949-1962 (Box 3)
    - Zaboly, Bela, 1944-1948 (Box 3)
    - Unidentifiable, 1942-1964; undated (Box 3)
  - Outgoing correspondence
    - [General], 1942-1959 (Box 4)
    - [General], 1961-1967; undated (Box 4)